<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Copyright 1999-2005 The Apache Software Foundation
Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->
<!--
// ======================================================================== 78
-->
<document>

    <properties>
        <title>Welcome</title>
    </properties>

    <body>

        <section name="About Struts 2">
            <a name="Welcome"/>

        <div style="text-align:center">
        <a href="http://cwiki.apache.org/WW/home.html"><img src="images/struts2-merger.png" alt="Struts 2 and WebWork merger"
        /></a>
        </div>
        
        <p>
        Struts 2 was originally known as WebWork 2. After working independently 
        for several years, the WebWork and Struts communities joined forces to 
        create Struts 2. This new version of Struts is designed to be simpler to 
        use and closer to how Struts was always meant to be.
        </p>
        
        </section>
        
        <section name="Key Changes">
            <ul>
            <li>
                <em>Smarter!</em> 
                <ul><li>
                    <strong>Improved Design</strong> - All Struts 2 classes are based on interfaces. 
                    Core interfaces are HTTP independent.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Intelligent Defaults</strong> - Most configuration elements have a default 
                    value that we can set and forget. 
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Enhanced Results</strong> - Unlike ActionForwards, Struts 2 Results can
                    actually help prepare the response. 
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Enhanced Tags</strong> - Struts 2 tags don't just output data, but provide 
                    stylesheet-driven markup, so that we can create consistent pages 
                    with less code.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>First-class AJAX support</strong> - The AJAX theme gives interactive 
                    applications a significant boost. 
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Stateful Checkboxes</strong> - Struts 2 checkboxes do not require special 
                    handling for false values.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>QuickStart</strong> - Many changes can be made on the fly without restarting 
                    a web container. 
                </li></ul></li>
                <li>
                    <em>Easier!</em> 
                <ul>
                <li>
                    <strong>Easy-to-test Actions</strong> - Struts 2 Actions are HTTP independent and 
                    can be tested without resorting to mock objects. 
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Easy-to-customize controller</strong> - Struts 1 lets us customize the request 
                    processor per module, Struts 2 lets us customize the request handling 
                    per action, if desired. 
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Easy-to-tweak tags</strong> - Struts 2 tag markup can be altered by changing 
                    an underlying stylesheet. Individual tag markup can be changed by 
                    editing a FreeMarker template. No need to grok the taglib API!
                    <em>JSP, FreeMarker, and Velocity tags are fully supported.</em>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Easy cancel handling</strong> - The Struts 2 Cancel button can go directly to 
                    a different action. 
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Easy Spring integration</strong> - Struts 2 Actions are Spring-aware. Just 
                    add Spring beans!
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Easy plugins</strong> - Struts 2 extensions can be added by dropping in a JAR. 
                    No manual configuration required! Bundled plugins add support for JavaServer Faces, 
                JasperReports, JFreeChart, Tiles, and more ...
                </li></ul></li>
                <li>
                <em>POJO-ier!</em> 
                <ul>
                <li>
                    <strong>POJO forms</strong> - No more ActionForms! We can use any JavaBean we like or 
                    put properties directly on our Action classes. No need to use all 
                    String properties! 
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>POJO Actions</strong> - Any class can be used as an Action class. We don't 
            even have to implement an interface! 
                </li></ul></li></ul>

            <p>
                For more, <a href="http://cwiki.apache.org/WW/home.html"><strong>visit Getting Started</strong></a>.
            </p>
            
        </section> 
        <section name="Distributions">

        <p>For your convenience, a one-stop <strong>all</strong> 
        distribution is available. Individual elements of the distribution 
        may also be downloaded separately.</p>
        <table>
            <tr>
            <td><a href="http://people.apache.org/builds/struts/2.0.1/struts-2.0.1-all.zip">all</a></td>
            <td>The entire distribution, including all the elements. (43mb)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
            <td><a href="http://people.apache.org/builds/struts/2.0.1/struts-2.0.1-apps.zip">apps</a></td>
            <td>The example applications, as ready-to-deploy WARs. (22mb) </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
            <td><a href="http://people.apache.org/builds/struts/2.0.1/struts2-blank-2.0.1.war">blank</a></td>
            <td>Just the blank application, ready to deploy as a template for new development. (Also included in apps.) (3mb)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
            <td><a href="http://people.apache.org/builds/struts/2.0.1/struts-2.0.1-docs.zip">docs</a></td>
            <td>The documentation, as provided on the website. (11mb)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
            <td><a href="http://people.apache.org/builds/struts/2.0.1/struts-2.0.1-lib.zip">lib</a></td>
            <td>The essential dependencies, including the Struts 2 JARs. (3mb)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
            <td><a href="http://people.apache.org/builds/struts/2.0.1/struts-2.0.1-src.zip">src</a></td>
            <td>The source code for the framework, ready to build as a Maven project. (18mb)</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
            <td><a href="http://people.apache.org/builds/struts/2.0.1/struts-2.0.1-j4.zip">sj4</a></td>
            <td>The Java 1.4 versions of the Struts and XWork JARs (prepared using RetoTranslator). (2mb)</td>
            </tr>
         </table>
            
            <ul><li>The Struts 2 distributions are classified "test-build" quality but are suitable for new development by early adopters.</li></ul>

        </section>        
                
        <section name="Maven Snapshots">
        <p>
            When a distribution is first made available, it is rated as a development build or "snapshot". Later, the quality of the distribution may be upgraded to "Beta" or "General Availability", based on feedback from the community, and then made available through ibiblio and other public Maven repositories. To obtain an early distribution via Maven, you can specify the ASF Snapshot repository in your POM. 
        </p>
        
        <p><pre><code>
        &lt;repositories>
          &lt;repository>
            &lt;id>ASF_SNAPSHOT_M2&lt;/id>
            &lt;name>ASF Maven 2 Snapshot&lt;/name>
            &lt;url>http://people.apache.org/repo/m2-snapshot-repository&lt;/url>
          &lt;/repository>
        &lt;/repositories>
        </code></pre></p>
                
        <p>
        For more about Apache Struts 2 see
        <a href="http://cwiki.apache.org/WW/home.html">
          Getting Started.
        </a>
        </p>
        
        </section>        

    </body>
</document>
