<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
// ======================================================================== 78
-->
<document>

    <properties>
        <title>Welcome</title>
    </properties>

    <body>

        <section name="About Apache Struts 2">
            <a name="Welcome"/>

        <div style="text-align:left;min-height:200px">
        <a href="docs/home.html"><img src="images/struts2-merger2.png" alt="Struts 2 and WebWork merger" hspace="16" align="left"/></a>

        <p>
         <strong>Apache Struts 2 is an elegant, extensible framework</strong> for creating enterprise-ready Java web applications.
         The framework is designed to streamline the full development cycle,
         from building, to deploying, to maintaining applications over time.
        </p>

        <p>
         Apache Struts 2 was originally known as WebWork 2.
         After working independently for several years,
         the WebWork and Struts communities joined forces to create Struts<sup>2</sup>.
         This new version of Struts is simpler to use and
         closer to how Struts was always meant to be.
        </p>
        </div>
        <div>
        <table><tr><td>
        <a href="http://struts.apache.org/download.cgi#struts20111">
          <div style="background:url(images/download.gif) no-repeat scroll 0%; width:200px; min-height:80px; float:left;position:relative;margin:5px">
            <span style="top:15px;position:absolute;color:white;padding-left:10px">
              <small>version 2.0.11.1</small>
              <br />
              <span style="font-weight: bold; font-size:140%">Download Now</span>
            </span>
          </div>
        </a>
        </td><td>
        <a href="http://struts.apache.org/2.x/docs/home.html" style="margin:10px">
          <div style="background:url(images/help.gif) no-repeat scroll 0%; width:200px; min-height:80px; float:left;position:relative;margin:5px">
            <span style="top:15px;position:absolute;color:white;padding-left:10px">
              <span style="font-weight: bold; font-size:140%">Get Started</span>
            </span>
          </div>
        </a>
        </td><td>
        <a href="http://cwiki.apache.org/S2PLUGINS/home.html" style="margin:10px">
          <div style="background:url(images/plugins.gif) no-repeat scroll 0%; width:200px; min-height:80px; float:left;position:relative;margin:5px">
            <span style="top:15px;position:absolute;color:white;padding-left:10px">
              <span style="font-weight: bold; font-size:140%">Plugin Registry</span>
            </span>
          </div>
        </a>
        </td></tr>
        </table></div>
        </section>

        <section name="Build! Deploy! Maintain!">
            <ul>
            <li>
                <em>Build!</em>
                <ul>
                <li>
                    <strong>Easy startup</strong> - Jumpstart new projects with our bootstrap tutorial and template application or Maven archetype.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Improved Design</strong> - Code clean against HTTP-independant framework interfaces.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Enhanced Tags</strong> - Code less with stylesheet-driven form tags that provide their own markup.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Stateful Checkboxes</strong> - Avoid special handling with smart checkboxes that know when they are toggled.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Flexible Cancel Buttons</strong> - Go directly to a different action on cancel.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>First-class AJAX support</strong> - Add interactivity and flexibility with AJAX tags that look and feel just like standard Struts tags.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Easy Spring integration</strong> - Inject dependencies into Actions using Spring without glue code or red tape. (Plexus support also available.)
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Enhanced Results</strong> - Do more with speciality results for JasperReports, JFreeChart, Action chaining, and file downloading.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>POJO forms</strong> -  No more ActionForms! Use any JavaBean to capture form input or
                    put properties directly on an Action class. Use both binary and String properties!
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>POJO Actions</strong> - Use any class as an Action class -- even the
                    interface is optional!
                </li>
                <!-- Experimental
                <li>
                    strong>Zero Configuration</strong> - Optionally, replace XML configuration with convention and annotation.
                </li>
                -->
                </ul></li>

                <li>
                    <em>Deploy!</em>
                <ul>
                <li>
                    <strong>Easy plugins</strong> - Add framework extensions by dropping in a JAR.
                    No manual configuration required! Bundled plugins add support for JavaServer Faces,
                    JasperReports, JFreeChart, Tiles, and more ...
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Integrated profiling</strong> - Peek inside Struts<sup>2</sup> to find where the cycles are going!
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Precise Error Reporting</strong> - Flip directly to the location and line of an error.
                </li>
                <!-- Experimental
                <li>
                    <strong>Easy portlets</strong> - Automatic portlet support allows portal and servlet
                    deployments with no code changes.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>REST-ful URLs</strong> - Use search-engine friendly URLs, like category/action/movie/Thrillers.
                </li>
                -->
                </ul></li>
                <li>
                <em>Maintain!</em>
                <ul>
                <li>
                    <strong>Easy-to-test Actions</strong> - Test Struts<sup>2</sup> Actions directly,
                    without resorting to mock HTTP objects.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Intelligent Defaults</strong> - Skip obvious and redundant settings. Most framework configuration
                    elements have a default value that we can set and forget. Say it once!
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Easy-to-customize controller</strong> - Customize the request handling
                    per action, if desired. Struts<sup>2</sup> only does what you want it to do!
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Integrating Debugging</strong> - Research problem reports with built-in
                    debugging tools.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <strong>Easy-to-tweak tags</strong> - Customize tag markup by editing a FreeMarker
                    template. No need to grok the taglib API!
                    <em>JSP, FreeMarker, and Velocity tags are fully supported.</em>
                </li>
                </ul></li></ul>

            <subsection>
            <p>
            To download the framework, visit
            <a href="http://struts.apache.org/download.cgi#struts206">
               Apache Struts Distributions.
            </a>
            For more about Apache Struts 2, visit
            <a href="docs/home.html">
              Getting Started.
            </a>
            For more about framework extensions, visit the
            <a href="http://cwiki.apache.org/S2PLUGINS/home.html">
              Struts 2 Plugin Registry.
            </a>
            For help with migrating, visit our
            <a href="http://struts.apache.org/2.x/docs/migration-guide.html">
               Migration Guide.
            </a>
            </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>

        <section name="Platform Requirements">

        <p>
        Apache Struts 2 requires:
        </p>

        <ul>
            <li>Servlet API 2.4</li>
            <li>JSP API 2.0</li>
            <li>Java 5</li>
        </ul>

        <p>
         An alternate set of JARs for Java 4 are also available.
         See the "J4" distribution.
        </p>

        <p>
         For a full list of requirements, including dependencies used by optional plugins,
         see <a href="http://struts.apache.org/2.x/struts2-core/dependencies.html">Project Dependencies</a>
        </p>

        </section>

        <section name="Licensing of Apache Struts Distributions">
        <p>
            Apache Struts 2 source code and documentation is
            licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one
            or more contributor license agreements. See the NOTICE file
            included in distribution for additional information
            regarding copyright ownership. The ASF licenses the source
            code and documentation files in our Apache Struts distribution
            to you under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
            you may not use the Apache Struts product except in compliance
            with the License.
        </p>

        <p>
            You may obtain a copy of the License at
            <a href="http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0">
            http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0</a>.
        </p>

        <p>
            Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
            software distributed under the License is distributed on an
            "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
            KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
            specific language governing permissions and limitations
            under the License.
        </p>

        </section>
    </body>
</document>
