<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
Copyright 1999-2005 The Apache Software Foundation
Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
-->
<!--
// ======================================================================== 78
-->
<document>

    <properties>
        <title>Welcome</title>
    </properties>

    <body>

        <section name="About Struts 2">
            <a name="Welcome"/>

        <div style="text-align:center">
        <img src="images/struts2-merger.png" alt="Struts 2 and WebWork merger" />
        </div>
        <p>
        Apache Struts 2 is an open source Java web framework that seeks to make it easy to build, deploy, and maintain modern web applications.  Struts 2 is the successor to the popular <a href="../1.x/">
        Struts 1</a> web application framework, as well as a product of a merger between the <a href="../">Apache Struts</a> and <a href="http://www.opensymphony.com/webwork">OpenSymphony WebWork</a> projects.  
        </p>
        <section name="Key Features">
            <a name="KeyFeatures"/>
        <p>
        How does Struts 2 make web development easier both to develop and maintain?  The framework has:
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>A flexible, plain old Java object (POJO)-based architecture to structure your code and pages, yet stay out of your way</li>
          <li>A theme-enabled tag library supporting JSP, Velocity, and Freemarker</li>
          <li>Built in support for complex Javascript and Ajax widgets</li>
          <li>A simple plugin framework to integrate with third-party libraries like JavaServer Faces, JasperReports, and JFreeChart.</li>
          <li>Built-in debugging tools supporting profiling, problem reports, and interactive object model queries.</li>
          <li>Automatic portlet support allowing portal and servlet deployments with no code changes</li>
          <li>Quick start development tools like Maven archetypes, automatic reloading configuration files, and bootstrap tutorials.</li>
        </ul>
        
        <section name="Architecture in a Nutshell">
        
        </section>
        <p>Struts 2 provides a flexible control layer based on standard
        technologies like Java Filters, JavaBeans, ResourceBundles, Locales,
        and XML.  In a nutshell, it looks like this:
        </p>
        <div style="text-align:center">
        <img src="images/struts2-arch.png" alt="Struts 2 Architecture" />
        </div>
        <p>
        And it flows like this:
        </p>
        <ol>
          <li>The user's browser requests the page</li>
          <li>The Filter Dispatcher looks at the request and determines the appropriate Action</li>
          <li>The Interceptors apply common functionality to the request like workflow, validation, and file upload handling</li>
          <li>The Action executes, usually storing and/or retrieving information from the database</li>
          <li>The Result renders the output, be it HTML, images, or PDF, to the browser</li>
        </ol>
 
        <p>
        For more About Struts 2 see
        <a href="http://cwiki.apache.org/WW/home.html">
          Getting Started.
        </a>
        </p>
        </section>
      </section>

    </body>
</document>
